Digitization is about automation and innovation, but the new here is that this requires supplementary strengths.
Bottomed on common values and that we have a smooth control.
I will end with some concrete examples of that
in my daily work.
Together with regrets, regrets and Sunsvall
is the guinea pig for collective digitalisation.
There is incredibly important
to distinguish precisely this supplementary strength that
itself
Requires that we change logic.
I will talk a lot about having to change logic.
What do I really mean by that
To shift logic
Yeah, well
Maybe what sets collective digitization with collaboration.
There we do not have really varying logic that
a goal.
If we need to change logic, you can ask.
Yes, this is a bit tricky indeed for
not infrequently I meet after all
context where one thinks this goes all the
Excellent within the existing logic.
The challenges we face, you have seen figures as 125 percent we will perform with 75 percent of resources.
We also have economies that fall like stone.
I came very recently from one
Meeting in my daily work
In Sundsvall municipality there
The economy looks sad.
We try then, or we, I have my frustration
to use the existing logic to solve that problem.
It's Baptism.
But not everyone who sees it.
So we need number one then think like this.
Should we change the calculation
Does not become as vulnerable.
We can
With the help of collective digitalisation create more equal welfare.
Digitally within
frantesa, because it is after all
much of it we have
Meet by today and more and more in the future is the digital service.
If we get an equal digital service, we will also get a more equal
welfare.
We can talk about a school, a school regardless of municipality.
It does not matter if the school is in one or the other municipality.
As residents, we will experience greater equality.
It may not be so careful that I
Do everything I can to make my child come into this particular school.
I'm frustrated or I'm happy, it has happened too.
And so he just "but Marcus, is like this" and then he draws a picture.
He draws another picture that I will show as well.
Institutionally
work, if you think
What I want to do or the institutional contractor wants to do so is to change
to maybe also counteract
Nonsense.
This is something that we
should end with.
Or
Then we should start with and do instead.
It can be very difficult or it is very difficult.
It depends very much on which
That it requires slightly different properties.
Now I'm actually talking about
Various archetypes of institutional contractors for it is not a person but it is required
an entire team, it requires a whole
Village of this kind of
characteristics.
But if one highlights something that Elissa is doing so well
I think in the work of developing visionary
strategies that help shift logic
that's how it is
Abstraction, idealism and long risers of analytical reasoning.
She highlights as the most important and in abstraction so you mean that you need to construct a visionary strategy.
And to do so, one must have the ability to free yourself from details.
It is easy to end up in details
and not perhaps then instead focus on
dimensions at a higher level
Which can be a little blurred or a little like this you end up in the fog and I don't really see I see contours but I can't put words into it.
But that one then has the ability to identify structural
element
in a problem.
It is an ability that is incredibly important then to make this pretty big step into another logic.
Idealism is about striving for perfection
becomes very difficult.
We are not everywhere.
We don't have all answers but trying to talk about these contours
as fast as possible and
get others to
Turn it.
So this is like
collective action
Even in this process.
And together with Fredrik has the opportunity to put words on
This diffuse and it is extremely valuable.
David and Goliath
Think so much about productivity.
It dissolves.
We raise the tax or we
closes a school.
That logic is not in the private sector at all in the same way.
But there is something in the municipality
As I experience and the state and authority also where I worked before
which is awkward.
If you take a pardon left there and crises outer hands facilitate.
There we also have one
Good paper about
Action The Double H Sword of Urgency
by Fred Berg and
And Premark that describes that it can actually go in two roads.
Quite exciting because it is doing it right now.
Ånge chooses a completely different path
And be able to put words into it.
So well one
Although painful in a way for me.
And my employees, it will be an incredibly good study opportunity to actually see this in practice.
But what we need is to do the institutional work and try to change this logic.
It is legitimacy.
And to counteract
this
Actually here the logic that makes you
Premiers as well
the existing one.
To establish the existing one.
To try to respond to it in some way.
There it helps if you look up in the picture.
External parties.
To get confirmation from outside.
Incredibly important.
To have others to tell you that this is the right way forward or to
that part
gets like some kind of confirmation
Leofanten.
What is this picture it was really
an attempt to
describe
the collective digitalisation as anything other than we
Playing football in a team or we cycle in a cluster.
Here
We create
A new logic that has the best of qualities from two different animals.
We have the leopard which is very fast and smooth.
And so we have the elephant that is big back
linked to the abilities required in it.
This is some kind of
Create new types of norms.
It is a process that makes us
In this sense trying to shift logic there
we take
trying to identify the
characteristics that we want to preserve or that we want to infect or as we want
replace other parts with in
Actually both each other but I see that here has the little one
The organization, the small municipality, a bigger role to play than the big one.
The small municipality really needs the most resources for many other things already there.
Then is valued in an awareness that it is not possible to solve